um so it was kind of prompted by one of
the things you mentioned in the last
discussion we had
about uh you know these various
contexts um that would describe
different contemplations or um
developments and then at the end bu
would say now practice J don't be
negligent um
and so basically it's
basically it's
um CU about Jana basically it's
something
that uh I think I I have like this kind
of notion lingering still or part of it
that um from kind of the views I would
have had before that Jan is like this
very specific
lofty um
state that is almost
like I mean you the way I used to be was
like a kind of taboo almost when I would
read the this the I kind of can't allow
myself to even sort of think
but and it was kind of that was one of
the reasons that I was finding this um
PDF kind of useful just the way he
present answer is like well actually
that should be the that is the
meditation basically that is the
training that is the training that's how
you should be spending most of your
day yeah by and by meditation does not
mean concentration yes meditation
meaning in the
original sort of usage of that word
which is basically to contemplate
reflect Ponder M um and actually yeah I
think I looked into that comes from the
Latin the same route as to medicate to
the same route as to medicate to
heal so it was when you basically
developing mental Clarity that results
in healing up of mental suffering even
originally that's how it was that what
it meant like to develop that Clarity
and understanding they would heal you so
to speak internally that's what
meditation means and it's like yeah the
first healing up would be the first
genre oh is there is there more than
this yeah yeah there's second one
there's a third one there's the fourth
one and so
on but um that's why I don't like the
word meditation because it's just it's
impossible to separate it from
concentration practices today doesn't
matter how much you qualify
it um so yeah go
on um so if you're meditating in that
sense purifying your mind from the UNH
wholesome States the whole day you are
practicing jna MH and Janna is lofty
from the point of view of those who
don't have it yeah that's it's mystified
that's what I mean by
lofty but if you're
actually practicing the janas the way
the Sut is described as we mentioned
today like you have so many sutas that
talk about Jana in the section on samadi
or whatever like samala Su they
clearly stops saying indria
SAR restraining of your
senses then leads to he doesn't give um
he doesn't U grasp the
nimas of the central perceptions sight
sound smell taste touches so the things
don't invade his mind he goes about his
days training like that day in day out
doesn't matter so first containing his senses
matter so first containing his senses
then stuff that comes up internally he's
not f in it latching onto it he's not
trying to get rid of it it's not his
creation he's just basically not
grasping the baits that are being
presented mentally and who knows for how
long then the says on another occasion
then he does not he overcomes the
central desire he overcomes the ill will
he overcomes SL Doro restlessness he
overcomes doubt and then he starts
giving the example oh he goes to
seclusion he starts frequently the
secluded dwellings basically empty of
people empty of others again but who
knows how
long well for as long as it's
necessary then the mind is withdrawn
from the hindrances then he feels the
release from the sense of being indebted
being enslaved being imprisoned being
starved all those things and then he
enters and ab in first J so it's like oh
that's the practice of that's the method
quote unquote of Jan
it's Taming of the senses not giving
into the mental images not allowing them
to Center Stage as we say that's
basically what it means not grasping the
signs and
features um spending most of your time
in seclusion with that mental attitude
practicing those those contexts and
purifications literally meditations
healing UPS cleaning UPS um and then the
mind is uh basically feels like it's
it's relieved of the burden the debt and
the um enslavement and that's the first
genre so somebody who starts practicing
that the more they're purifying these
things the more they investing time in
that sort of um
correct um
taming well the less mystical J will
will feel because they effectually going to
feel because they effectually going to
be relieving themselves of of that
assumed weight of some sort of Duty as I
said burden enslavement and so
on but for some bizarre
reason that's completely omitted from
the modern view of what Jan is and how
to practice modern Buddhist view modern
scholar view modern early Buddhist text
sutta study views it's like no jna is
this method that you that you
practice mechanically they will somehow
unify your mind magically into this
state of elevated concentration and that
will help you see things
clearly it's not that you don't see
things clearly because you're not
concentrated enough you don't see them
clearly because you keep throwing the
pollutions in the water through your
body speech and mind actions that you're
completely unaware
of like literally you are mudding the
water yourself while you're trying to
see what's at the bottom of it
so it's like you got to stop doing it
and then you that that's
already purpos
served why would you then need to
practice some some method of absorbing
yourself into a single object when
things are already
clear no it's just predicated on The
View that somehow concentration will
magically take me to the place I want to
be without me grinding my way to it
so it's
like all the talk about Jas and they
talk about what like how to get them
through IND seclusion not grasping the
signs and features overcome hindrances
and then mention janas as a result of
that and this whole stuff that precedes
the Jan is just overlooked and then all
people see is the Jan and thinking and
pondering and they try to make sense of
that and how to do it and how to apply
how to sustain the thought or how to
evaluate rightly how to attend to it
it's like no that's the result of all
this stuff that you well should have
done um and uh and if you if you take it
that way you real that's you practice
J for
years hindrances not allowing the center stage
hindrances not allowing the center stage
of unsuitable images while they're there
trying to pressure you enduring them on
that level not feeding them not reaching
out to get rid of them through AV verion
it's like yeah that you're practicing
John
basically sustaining that until it
becomes like
the way your mind is established yes yes
so like for example
say you are restraining your senses
you're not allowing the sent stage of of
nitas to take over um you're not um you
are dwelling in in seclusion and your
mind is free from
hindrances even if for a brief period of
time even if you don't necessarily feel
the the relief of crossing the desert
successfully or paying the debt and
being released from a
prison that was still Jan it's just
obviously Jan that you haven't steady
your mind in and once you do then these
pleasures of relief will come that you
can pervade your body with uh
but pleasure of Jan is not the Jana
that's the result of it that's the point
so that's why those Su start to make it
sense more when says practice Jana even
for a finger snap it will be very it
will be streams of Merit people will
think ah for a finger snap of
experiencing this ecstatic pleasure
means no practice it you know practicing
the Ecstasy of
pleasure exactly practice it means no no
no you making the right effort on the
right level and even if it's set up
rightly even for a finger snap it will
be
meritorious now imagine if it's longer
than a finger snap well that's when you
would come to realize that you are debt
free not a slave cross the desert and
everything else and actually that's kind of a good
else and actually that's kind of a good
point as well because if the emphasis is
on uh that you know um feeling the sense
of relief being what what J is you would
be like well kind of blocking it by kind
of but wait where is the feeling of
relief where is the obviously that's how
you would be yeah well or even worse
like people certainly the the modern
meditation quote unquote
Masters um they try to
reconstruct the
supposed pleasure of relief of Jan
through fabricating basically physical
pleasure
like building it up from
Sensations spreading the sensations
through your body until they accumulate
enough it's like that's completely upset
like so it's like oh I still haven't I
don't even know I'm In Deed I don't even
recognize my position of being enslaved
I just know I'm supposed to feel the
relief of it so I'll just fabricate
through basically forcing my body to
feel it bit by bit here and there until
it f finally hopefully magically adds up
and then that frees me from that because
I feel like I'm thatt free no freedom
from debt comes from recognizing the
debt and recognizing that you're free
from it Freedom From Slavery comes from
recognizing that you were enslaved to
begin with freedom from Desert
same actually so imagine just imagine
that
like you do recognize now
that like I don't know you would have to
now completely uproot your current life
go back to your home country cuz I don't
know if you don't go there and work and
serve and pay off your debt well they'll
come after you and everybody will be in
prisoned that you know just something
horrible so you have to go and do it so
you feel the weight of your
situation it's like you're not your own
Master as the simul says you have to go
and do it factually cuz like you might
lose your life if you
don't and then you know with all that
worry with all that
recognition you go and do it or for one
reason or the other you basically pay it
back through your own effort and now you
feel the relief of
that that relief will be physically felt
for days depending on how much debt there
days depending on how much debt there
was especially if your life was at stake
or same
terminal illness as we said before and
then you suddenly realize after living
under that diagnosis for like say a
year and then you realize then they tell
you no sorry I was wrong you're healthy
it's fine you would feel relieved for
days physically like whether you sit
walk lay down doesn't matter you're
going to feel physical pleasure of the
just sense of ease that comes out of it
that's why all the Jas when they
describe the pleasure it's compared to
coolness and Cool Breeze or cool water
or clear cool
pond so yes it's felt physically on
account of mental
relief but now imagine you just trying
to fabricate the relief while your
diagnosis hasn't changed you haven't
found a way out of illness that's modern
meditation techniques completely upside down
I was going to say like in a way
um at least from memory now but in the
way that the that passage goes in the
sutas it's like
um you it says in the same way as long
as these five hindrances are not
uprooted in him he regards it as a de as
and then it's like it's the right next
thing it's like the next sentence but
when they are uprooted in him he feels
it as a relief so it's like in a way you
could say I think that like fully
recognizing the extent
of the death impr imprisonment is
actually like the way to free yourself
from it there's nothing in between like
you don't need to kind of if you're not
free from the debt it's actually more
like because you aren't you don't
recognize the full the full extent of
the debt you are still like
um perpetuating the debt unknowingly so
to say or on some level kind of that
you're overlooking overlooking it
yeah so yeah when the Su say
pervade body with that
pleasure with that relief of being that
free yeah
sure pervade the body with that pleasure
don't don't try to deny it because it's
not un wholesome see it came from mental
uprooting of the five hindrances it
didn't come from physical tactile
sensation building and that
relief that you will factually feel
physically as a result of mental
freedom from the constraint of the five
hindrances by all means enjoy it
spread it through your body make
recognize that let it affect your whole
body so to
speak so why why would you do that why
is that a relevant
practice maybe to keep you going in that
direction yeah it's like that just say
like a a treat for the
Mind encouraging yeah
well exactly so but why why the entire body
exactly so but why why the entire body
like you know every every one of those
simile is that no part of the body is
left unpervaded by that
pleasure so does the pleasure come from
the body no it comes from being the
relief of so comes from chitt yeah chitt
relieved from
being free from from dodging the
bullet so it's
so it's
not localized in the body because it
didn't come from the body it didn't come
from the sense of
touch it comes from the CH which is
technically well certainly nowhere in
any part of the body it's simply a
phenomenon that's neither here nor there
in regard to to your physicality and in
regard to your um feeling well
perceptions externally yeah but feeling
you could say that
yeah so chitt is basically like a a
superimposed phenomenon in regard to the
totality of your body you could think of
it like like a source of
light that can either be illumin
illuminating your whole body or parts of
it if it's not bright enough or none of
it if if it's obstructed and clouded and
dark and
dim so if it's
unobstructed the entire
body feels
it but why would you then need to make
sure that is the entire body there no
parts of
it what what what are you doing then by
making sure that the pleasure of the
relief that comes from chitt being free
Chi's relief the pleasure of that you
make sure that the whole body is
illuminated by it not too much not too
little like that foam that you mix with
water just so there's no water seeping
nor it's too dry just to right extent
why because the non relief of
Jitter like when it's
um or let's say the absence of of light
MH comes from or is is related to taking
up the body
mhm um or yeah taking up the body which
is always done through specific it's not
it's it's like a very practical thing
it's not a kind of I mean it is rooted
in mental mental attitude but it is very
practically related to the way you use
certain parts of your body the way you
assume certain part parts of your body
so
um the perspective nrows down onto them
basically yes
um so but now CH is De free so it's it's
debt free
free
but that Deb freeness
yeah needs to
be kind of
yeah spread or like uh hammered in I
suppose so to like related to those he
needs to saturate those things those
things for it takes time so that they
cannot be taken up because the only reason you
be taken up because the only reason you
would be taking them up is through not
knowing the
alternative the only way you can take
them up is through overlooking them yeah
you overlook them you look past them you
took them up
for the very reason that's why naturally
if you're still concerned with sense
objects in the world and not practicing
indria Sam the beginning of Jana the
beginning of samadi you're very much
taking up your whole body yeah not just
parts of
it and which means now CH is even more
obscure even more
buried even more covered
up so you will
be the relief that comes from chitt you
would make
sure that it sort of illuminates your
whole body back forward everywhere
because you are the one who is just
through habitual non- illumination of
those parts you just Overlook them so in
other words the clearer that pleasure
illuminates the entire body the clearer
the separation between Chet and the body
is
no
overlap no mixing of the domains no
touching up nothing just clear
distinction and the clearer that
separation is means the more secluded chitt is from
is means the more secluded chitt is from
the domain of the five
senses how about the second gen
description
that it's like a underground lake with
an underground water source that fills
it up right to the brim not too much not
too little no external water source no
rain nothing comes to
it but it's just perfectly
full and uh cool From The Underground
Source not from any observable
Source what's the underground source
the simil what the source it doesn't
simil what the source it doesn't
appear because it if if it appears it's
on the level of the body it's on the
level of the senses it's on the level of
Mana the the mind
um so it's ch ch the underground the
mind is a yeah very V term so then you
can see another reason why you should be
see another reason why you should be
pervading the body
see cuz when Chet is
unobstructed there is nothing measuring
it
anymore so you not you're not perceiving
it you know the signs of the
Mind indicate the mind but they're not
the mind so underground source that you
mind so underground source that you
don't how do you know there's an
underground Source let's stick with the
lake how do you know there's an
underground source
because in the simil what does it say
the lake because it's the lake is full
with well it might have been filled
before the source might have blocked or
something but it was still
there the lake is cool yeah I was going
to say oh because the lake is clear and
cool clear and cold and cold and cold
yeah so it's the coolness
of that illumination let's put it that
way that's that's how you know chit is
there clean unobstructed so through
pervading your
body with the coolness of the
Illumination in the second J you are
basically just outlining CH even more
and more and
more without misconceiving it for one of
its nitas mhm
remember like in those early esses when
I saying that because of which now you
can know it's there but if you look at
it that's not it it's not it you made it
into something else well that's exactly
that principle whereby now it's not even
on the level of just like a reflection
and contemplation it's felt physically
that because of which so you don't need
to find the source you know because the
constant fresh cool water is just coming
MH filling up
and it's felt as well it's felt so your
exactly so
your um
um
indication of a
unobstructed bright brighter CH
CH
is that feeling that feeling of pity
that feeling of of um Mery Rapture Joy
which we translated in English that free
feeling of being that free that's felt
physically CU it doesn't come from
anything physical
mhm that's I mean said it many times
that's why janas are
janas are
completely outside of the scope of
craving cannot be undermined by the
underlying Tendencies because they don't come from
Tendencies because they don't come from
any basis where under underlying
Tendencies apply which is the five
senses and the mind
so it's completely not coming from any
direction of your five senses and Mano
so any direction of space and time in
terms of Mano operating that's not where
the pleasure comes from and you know
that it comes from basically from
freeing Mano from the pressure of the five
Mano from the pressure of the five
senses through not acting out of it
through practicing the through
restraining them through seclusion and
then through recognizing the death the
slavery the desert and freeing yourself
from that which we spoke about in other talks
that which we spoke about in other talks
you free yourself from that when you
tame your
chitt the animal the indications of the
animal in regard to those
things when the animal is not pressuring
you from Beyond so to
speak you realize oh I'm de free here
I'm at no risk anyal there is no danger
internally or externally and then the
animal also recognizes
that and it feels free and you as a
result of that experience the physical
relief so pervading your body in its
totality internally not externally
patching it up through statile
observation of your Sensations or breath
massages if you internally pervade your
whole body with that relief that comes
from the ch
it will become well if you do it
sufficiently long enough it will become
impossible for you to then misconceive
CH as any part of any phenomenon that
appears whether it's the five senses or
the mind and that's a liberated mind it
mind and that's a liberated mind it
cannot be bound anymore certainly not to
the five low Fates
how do you remove your sense
of I am from the picture of your
experience as a whole how do you remove
your sense of I
am the sense of I am that you have here
and now don't think
abely and say yes you are keeping the
precepts practice sens straint uh not
grasping the signs and features don't
not allowing them to Center
Stage dwelling in sufficient amount of
seclusion recognizing
hindrances what else do you do in regard
to the sense of I am that you do have
there what would be the way to free
yourself from
it you can say contemplating
impermanence daa
but why what for do you do it for your
sent self yes good point
well or you do it for cheetah exactly
you do it for cheetah so does that mean
cheah and does your sense self
that's re recognizing
the having the two points of view as you
would have said like the point of view
of chitt to your sense of self so to
speak or and your s the point of view of
your sense of self as a phenomenon in
regard to chitt so to
speak and having like and it has to be
be
complete well that's my question so when
do you know it's complete so how do you
get rid of the Sens
yourself when do you know it's complete
when it's not anymore back and
forth when I said complete I kind of
meant nothing else left out now complet
as in the sense of finished okay well I
I mean in the sense of finished so when
is when is it complet compl
completed when do you know the sense of
self is
gone is it because you stopped choosing
it or you you you stopped you stopped
attending to things
wrongly well it's when it's cheetah is
what like deactivated or I mean yeah I can
like deactivated or I mean yeah I can
only describe sense I can't describe it
um experientially yeah I I can only
describe it in terms of like relatively
speaking will describe it relatively
speaking like
um so when what so you you have uprooted
the sense of self when
what I mean relatively speaking when
cheetah relatively speaking when cheetah
is
is not wanting
to act out of or get rid
of but why would it would it affect your
cental
self cuz you know you had SAS and
brahans outside of the Buddhist
dispensation yeah who were able to free
themselves from craving for sensuality
thoroughly which means the cheah
completely fre from craving for any
anything that comes from the five senses
so yes of course they will be
contributing but that's not the main
factor what's the main
factor so when CH your sense of self is
you know your sense that you've uped
your sense of self is complete as and
finished yes when CH what when the wild
animal what well it's not wild obviously
by that point
M but basically when chitt doesn't
regard you anymore when he doesn't see
you as entity anymore you will be unable
to see yourself as one doesn't matter
how hard you try and that's when um
tagata or an Arun continues using the
designations I am I was this I will be
that without that having any
significance of self because the mind
completely does not take it up that
way and that's that whole kind of what's
the P
aara the I making Sankara the ch does
not you that zanaras are not your
activities they're ch's
activations so yes you need to learn
about anata you need to
contemplate and Dua and so on just so to
keep teaching the animal to stop
regarding you as
self as I am as oh look at this
guy and yes it's correct when animal is
sufficiently deactivated
from those
activations it will stop regarding you
yourself and then you will stop
regarding it yourself as
yourself so it's it's it's out of your
hands then so to speak an is out of your
hands you were ATA cuz the animal was
were seeing you too much of a person
basically because of its own Wilderness
that you were responsible for through
not taming it you tamed it became
unw you provided wisdom for it the
insights the 10 perceptions that they s
to talk about that you should be
providing your chitt for and he stopped
seeing you as a
person and mean CH to stop seeing as a
person there's nothing you can do about
it yourself why would you obviously
because you feel relieved of the burden
of personality
so would you say um practically
speaking it's basically
when none of the same like you can think
as much as you want like you would say
the designations you can think as much
as you want in terms of the same images
the same things that used to kind of
represent
you yeah but none of them
can not be can can kind of take on this
extra implication because even those
extra implications can't not be seen as
things yeah so the exactly exactly they
just seen as things the point
is the code of your sense of self that
you feel is the cheet perception of
you let's put it that
way you don't see CH you don't see that
where that core where that activation
comes from so you just bundle it all
together you start seeing Chet enough
like a prerequisite for sa party that
core will be
undermined everything else Remains the
shell of you
remains but the core is now switch off
gone destroyed that's the atada when it's
destroyed that's the atada when it's
abandoned then you might have remnants
well you will have remnance of I am and
stuff but the same principle
remains and that's also
see to the extent that you are
overlooking your internal body as the
totality of your experience as a whole
to that extent there is the basis for
that core of perception that comes from
CH seeing as a person for you to place
it somewhere mhm in that internal
totality of your body somewhere
peripherally the back neither here nor
there that's also why through realizing
that well backwards forwards the back of
my head front doesn't matter up down in
any direction physicality is there the
four grade elements nothing cannot be
part of this and that's how you
delineate chitt clearer and recognize
that the activating core of that heart
of I am it's actually ch just mistakenly
sees you as a person which is how you
make and Freer yes and when you
recognize that anything that chah would
be seeing the animal would be seeing
when it looks at you is the four Great
elements nothing else the bile the
skin the space in between the
wind then the Chet will stop it will
still see a maybe a remnant of what it
used to think was a full-blown person I
am but that whole source of aara and
mamara isn't it I'm making and mind
making that comes from CH is going to be
depleted while everything like even your
your speech patterns and ways of
expression and reference it remains
completely unchanged because that's not
where the self
was so that's also why it's relevant to
pervade with a cool Illuminating
pleasure of the hindrance free chitt the
entire extent of the totality of your
body internally so that the whole thing will
internally so that the whole thing will
be seen as external to
chitt no part left unilluminated
unpervaded thus no part can be assumed as a basis
thus no part can be assumed as a basis
for
that lingering senses of I am that might
be
remaining um no it reminded me also that
what you just said now and you said it
earlier as well but it reminded me of
what you were saying in regards to
anapanasati as well about um
contrasting the internal physicality of the body
the internal physicality of the body
with
the act of breathing Act of breathing
and the perception of
breathing and so as to yeah further
basically yeah delate outline the of the
extent of both exactly Yeah by outlining
the extent of the internal physicality
you're revealing what CH is
revealing what CH is
not what cannot be that's why after you
would have been doing these contrasting
practices in regard to the body then
sort of comes to the feelings and then
the
mind and so that's not um
could you say that's basically or it
could be thought of just another type of
description of Jan this was one question
I had or is it a completely different
thing no no of
course it's all J exactly okay good
contemplating dead bodies yeah it's they
will outline your own internal
physicality as unable it's j yeah it's
just different directions of approaching
it so
that's and I think I think commentary is
the traditional terada sort of with
sudim Maga and Company um kind of
understood that in the sense of through
studying the texts they saw that you
know the magical mystical genre occurs
out of all these different seemingly
different practices so I remember it was
some it was like some ter manual or
meditation long time ago there and it
was like basically compiling all the
um all the objects that can lead to Jan
on the basis of the sutas so he was
anapanasati he was contemplating corpses
it was loving kindness so it was all
presented as these different methods
they would magically take to Jan not
recognizing that actually doing those
things rightly is already J J exactly
this already what J is yeah so this is
really useful for me because that was
one of the big confusions I used to have
when reading the sutas It's like because
you know you asking what's the right
meditation and the answer is J but then
at the same time you have like all of
these different sutas seemingly talking
about different things nine percept
develop these nine perceptions and you
can see well yeah okay that's like makes
sense but then how does the you know
yeah where does J come into us and yeah
it simplifies things considerably Jana
is purification J is contemplation J is
meditation in the correct usage of that
term yeah J is not
concentration or like one of the things
I was thinking about asking as well um
in regards to this was yeah what we were
just speaking about this
um uh I suppose contemplation of or
percept developing perception of uh with
this this is without this this isn't or
as you were uh you would put it like the
two points of view thinking about that
or bearing this in mind um developing
that viewing
um yeah you're doing you're doing that
is that is another way of describing it
and it's very
efficient goes right to the
middle but you can see like even sense
restraint is is doing JN it's doing Sam
that's already the
beginning of freeing yourself from De
and the desert it's not like again it's
not something oh yeah yeah yeah we got
to do that but the you know the real
meat of the practice is this meth method
or something no no that is already
beginning of your CH
practice not allowing images take the
center stage I not grasping the signs
and features while they're there
pressuring you while you're enduring
them it's doing the J practice
dwelling in seclusion recognizing the
extent of the
hindrances that hinder you through the
movement of your wild animal because
you're wrongly attending to
it that's already jna
practice taming the wild animal giving
it rewards at the right time to
recognize for itself providing it with a
10 perceptions as that says that's
already J practice
when that whole
training on the basis of Prior
development of virtue and the non wrong
livelihood um when that whole practice
then is stable steady became your mode
of being as you said um you will feel de
free prison free cross the desert
successfully and now
don't fall from that state don't become
careless don't allow Center images don't
think you did the work because there's
still work to be
done so then you pervade your body with
that cool Illuminating pleasure of the
unobstructed cha that's
there superimposed to your experience of
your physicality totality internally as
a
whole until there's no parts left that
can serve as a basis for any Assumption
of I am in mind
and then when that's
developed make sure that you regard even
that purified bright clean free from
hindrances experience as but even this
is a death is a DT is a boil is a
burden nothingness is truly better and
then cheetah will turn away from that
and that's when there is nothing left no
more work to be
done that why this s to say
um one can become an arand on the basis
of the first J or the second or the
third or the fourth how well by fully
studying his mind in the first J and
then I instruct him okay now monk great
that pure blameless factually developed
mode of being that you would have
cultivated regard that now same as a d
as a de and CH W nothing to do with it
and that means nothing will be binding
you form or
formless traces of being so to
speak so for you it's to provide
clarify protect restrain the extent so
that you can recognize
it and illuminate it through your
instruction not through some mystical
Revelation you need to train it you need
to be providing these perceptions for it
you might not see it right away but if
you keep it in front of it that's your
bana that's your work the time will come
when it will look and see it and then it
will be impossible to not understand
it so that's the whole patient aspect of
practice